A racing second hand, a glittering shooting star!
عقرب دقائق مسرِع، مُذنّب لامع
Conan's logic is good medicine for hearts dried by modern society!
استنتاجات كونان دواء ممتاز للقلوب !التي جفّفها المجتمع الحديث
Today's stage is a giant mansion! My rival Heiji also plays a big role!
!مسرح اليوم قصر فسيح! يلعب خصمي هيجي دوراً كبيراً
He sees the single truth for what it is,
يرى الحقيقة الواحدة
His name? Detective Conan!
!اسمه المتحرّي كونان
"The Case of the Eminent Family's Strange Deaths, Part 1."
الجزء الأوّل
I'd expect nothing less from the head of the Nagato Group,
كما يُتوقع من قصر رئيس مجموعة شركات ناغاتو
which stands equal with Sonoko's family!
!التي تُكافئ عائلة سونوكو
Oh, you know Miss Sonoko?
تعرفين الآنسة سونوكو؟
She visited a few times when she was a little girl.
زارتنا بضعة مرّات في صغرها
"Miss" doesn't quite fit her, though.
رغم أنّ لقب "الآنسة" لا يلائمها
Why does someone that important want to see you?!
ما الذي يريده شخص بهذا المقام منك؟
He personally asked for the great Mori Kogoro!
!طلب حضور المتحرّي العظيم كوغورو موري شخصياً
He wants me to solve a big case!
!يريد منّي حلّ قضيّة كبيرة
Or make sure his wife isn't cheating.
قد يكون مجرّد تحرّي خيانة زوجيّة
What was that?!
!ماذا؟
Are you all right?!
!أأنت بخير؟
What are these holes around the pond?
ما خطب هذه الحفر حول البركة؟
We plan to plant new trees here by the week's end...
ننوي زرع أشجار جديدة هنا بنهاية الأسبوع
Pardon my lateness, but I am Take Kuranosuke,
أعتذر على التأخر في تقديم نفسي
the family's butler for the last two generations.
أنا تاكي كورانوسكي، كبير خدم العائلة للجيلين السابقين
Wow! The inside is amazing, too!
!المحيط الداخلي مذهل أيضاً
The master waits on the third floor.
ينتظركم السيّد في الطابق الثالث
There sure are lots of guards...
يوجد الكثير من الحرس
Naturally. It's a big case.
بالطبع، فهذه قضيّة كبيرة
Oh? Haven't I seen him before?
ماذا؟ هل رأيتُه قبلاً؟
Huh?! Find your first love?!
!ماذا؟! أجد محبوبتك الأولى؟
Me?! The great Mori Kogoro?!
أنا؟ المتحرّي العظيم موري كوغورو؟
Yes.
نعم
Nagato Dosan (60) President of Nagato Group
...أكّد لي صديقٌ قديم أنّك تستطيع
My old friend assured me you could...
(60) ناغاتو دوسان رئيس مجموعة شركات ناغاتو
...find her with lightning speed!
إيجادها بلمح البصر
But you didn't need to bring me here just to ask that...
لكن لم يكن هناك داعٍ لاستدعائي إذا كانت قضيّة بحث عن شخص فحسب
Too bad it wasn't a big case, huh?!
!يا للأسف، لم تكن قضيّة كبيرة
Do you have any photos of this woman?
ألديك صورة لهذه المرأة؟
No. We met during grade school.
التقيتُها في المدرسة الابتدائية، فكلّا
I don't even remember her face...
لا أتذكر وجهها حتّى
But lately, for some reason, I'm reminded of how lovely she was...
...لكنّي أفكّر بها لسببٍ ما مؤخراً
My late wife may not be happy to hear that, though...
...قد تحقد عليّ زوجتي الراحلة بكلامي هذا، لكن
I have no photographs,
لا صور لديّ
but I do know her name and her later whereabouts!
لكنّي أعرف اسمها ومكان عيشها التقريبيّ
Tell them, Hyuga-kun.
هيوغا-كن، أخبريه رجاءً
Certainly.
حسناً
Hyuga Miyuki (26) Mr. Nagato's Secretary
(26) هيوغا ميوكي سكرتيرة الرئيسة ناغاتو
Her name is Akagi Kotomi, from Kanagawa Prefecture.
اسمها أكاغي كوتومي، من محافظة كانيغاوا
After graduation, she married at age 29.
بعد التخرّج، تزوّجت في سنّ التاسعة والعشرين
She and husband Yamato Kohei had one child,
أنجبت وزوجها ياماتو كوهي طفلاً واحداً
but all three suddenly disappeared five years later.
لكن اختفى ثلاثتهم فجأةً بعد خمسة أعوام
You sure they didn't flee by night?
ألم يهربوا ليلاً فحسب؟
Unthinkable!
!مستحيل
Who's this old friend who recommended me, anyway?!
كما من هو صديقك القديم !الذي أوصى بي لك؟
That would be me.
كان أنا
And you are?
من أنت؟
He's the old friend I mentioned!
إنّه الصديق القديم الذي ذكرتُه
Osaka's Chief of Police, Hattori Heizo-kun!
هاتّوري هيزو الرئيس العام لشرطة أوساكا
Osaka's Chief of Police?!
!الرئيس العام لشرطة أوساكا؟
The one who's always on TV whenever something happens in Osaka?!
الذي يظهر على التلفاز دائماً عندما تقع قضيّة كبيرة في أوساكا؟
I thought he looked familiar...
...لا عجب أنّه بدا مألوفاً
Wait! Does that mean...?
...لحظة، أيعني ذلك
Heya, Kudo! How ya been?!
مرحباً يا كودو! كيف حالك؟
Hattori Heiji?!
!هاتّوري هيجي
Kudo?
كودو؟
What? They still don't know?
ماذا؟ لم تخبرهما بعد؟
Of course not, you moron!
!بالطبع لا يا أحمق
By "Kudo," do you mean...?
...أتقصد بكودو
I said "Kuro"! As in "thanks for your hard work"!
!قلتُ "كورو"! أي بُوركت جهودك
Oh, you have company, Father?
لديك ضيوف يا أبي؟
Nagato Nobuko (39), Eldest Daughter Nagato Yasue (32), Second Daughter
(39) ناغاتو نوبوكو الابنة الكبرى لعائلة ناغاتو
Oh, it's not just guests.
عجباً، ليس ضيوفاً فحسب
A vixen is here, as well.
بينهم ثعلبة أيضاً
I'm told you've been staying here recently.
سمعتُ أنّك كنتِ تبيتين هنا
What scheme are you cooking up?
ما الذي تخططين له؟
Come, now...
...على رسلك يا أختي
Now, now, Nobuko! I am unable to move!
مهلك يا نوبوكو، أنا غير قادر على الحركة كما ترين
I need her to send notes to the office...
أحتاجها لإرسال ملاحظات للشركة
A fax machine could do that!
يمكنك فعل ذلك بآلة فاكس
But it's not that simple...
الأمر ليس بتلك البساطة
Who are these gentlemen?
ومن أولئك الأشخاص؟
Detectives.
متحرّون
Detectives?!
متحرّون؟
Why are detectives here?
لمَ أتوا هنا؟
He called them here to ask them to find his first--
استدعاهم الرئيس لطلب البحث ...عن محبوبته الأولى
Nobody asked you!
!لم يسألك أحد
Hey, now...
...مهلك
You still have that filthy pen?
لا يزال معك هذا القلم القذر؟
I don't care if it's your dad's keepsake! It's creepy!
!لا أهتمّ إذا كان تذكاراً من أبيك، إنّه مقرف
Better watch out, or she'll steal your Mitsuaki-san, too!
عليكِ الاحتراس يا ياسوي-سان وإلّا ستسرق ميتسواكي-سان منك أيضاً
Sister!
!أختي
Such rudeness!
يا للوقاحة
I apologize, Hyuga-kun.
آسف يا هيوغا-كن
She's simply upset that she hasn't found a man yet...
إنّها متضايقة لأنّها لم ترتبط برجل في هذا العمر فحسب
Yes, I know.
نعم، أعي ذلك
I doubt she'll ever find one...
لا أظنّها سترتبط لبقيّة حياتها
Well, I should return to the office.
سأرجع للمكتب إذاً
Oh, Hyuga-kun. I'd like to make the announcement tonight,
هيوغا-كن! أودّ الإعلان عن الأمر الليلة
so if you do pity my son...
...لذا إن كنتِ تشفقين على ابني
I don't pity him at all! This is our fate!
لا أشفق عليه البتّة، فهذا قدرنا
A "bond of flames" has connected us for a long time now...
جمعتنا رابطة لهب لوقتٍ طويل
"Bond of flames"?
رابطة لهب؟
You two were in the same kendo club?
كنتما في نفس نادي الكيندو؟
Yes, Nagato-san used to beat me down like a demon!
نعم، كان ناغاتو يسحقني كالشيطان دوماً
Incidentally, Heizo. About the matter...
...بالمناسبة يا هيزو، بخصوص ذاك الموضوع
Yes. I had the guards double-check, but...
...نعم، طلبتُ من الحرّاس التحقّق، لكن
Who're you?!
!مـ-من أنت؟
My son, Hideomi.
ابني هيدومي
His face was burned
احترق وجهه في حادثة
in an accident long ago.
عندما كان في المدرسة الثانويّة
Nagato Hideomi (36) Eldest Son & Novelist
(36) ناغاتو هيدومي الابن الأكبر لناغاتو، روائيّ
Ever since, he's...
...وهو على حاله هذا مُذ آنذاك
I think modern plastic surgery could fix most of it,
أظنّ أنّ العمليات التجميلية الحديثة تستطيع إصلاح معظم الأضرار الآن
but he's against the idea.
لكنّه يعارض الفكرة
Yeah, it's a happy ending, all thanks to the accident.
(ناغاتو ميتسواكي (36 زوج ياسوي (أخذ اسم عائلة ناغاتو)، رئيس ناغاتو للمقاولات
Right, Hideomi?
صحيح يا هيدومي؟
Hey! Hideomi! Wait! What're you so mad for?
هيدومي، انتظر! ما الذي أغضبك؟
I wish you a happy birthday, Father!
!عيد ميلاد سعيد أيّها الأب
Thank you!
شكراً
I'd appreciate it if you'd give me the title of president in return...
سأكون مُمتناً لو منحتني ...منصب الرئيس في المقابل
I'm just kidding!
!أمزح فحسب
I must be getting back to Osaka...
عليّ الرجوع لأوساكا
Oh? You're not going to celebrate with us tonight?
ماذا؟ لن تبقى للاحتفال معنا الليلة؟
There's also the matter at hand...
فلا يزال هناك ذاك الموضوع
It's alright. I'll be leaving him in my place.
لا تقلق، سأتركه مكاني
He's still green, but he's got good intuition.
لا يزال قليل الخبرة، لكنّ حدسه حاد
I'm sure he'll be of use to Detective Mori!
سيكون ذا فائدة للمتحرّي موري بلا شك
Use?
ذا فائدة؟
Happy birthday, Father!
!عيد ميلاد سعيد يا أبي
Happy birthday, Sir!
!عيد ميلاد سعيد سيّدي
I'd like to use this opportunity to make an announcement.
هناك ما أودّ الإعلان عنه في هذه المناسبة
My son Hideomi and Hyuga Miyuki-san are engaged to be married!
!سيتزوّج ابني هيدومي وهيوغا ميوكي-سان
Is this true, Sir?
أهذا صحيح سيّدي؟
Yes. I've been having her stay here so she would grow used to the house!
نعم، طلبتُ منها الإقامة هنا كي تعتاد على العيش في المنزل
Oh, so that's why!
!هذا السبب إذاً
Oh? Where is Nobuko-ojousama going?
ماذا؟ أين تذهبين سيّدتي نوبوكو؟
Don't mind her!
دعها وشأنها
She's just the only single person left!
إنّها الفتاة الوحيدة العزباء الآن
Say, I don't see Hideomi...
...بالمناسبة، لا أرى هيدومي
He's probably embarrassed. I'll go get him.
لا بدّ أنّه يشعر بالإحراج، سأذهب لجلبه
Okay, Hattori! Out with it!
!هاتّوري! تكلّم
Out with what?
أتكلّم بماذا؟
The real reason you brought us here!
!الدافع الحقيقيّ لجلبك لنا هنا
It's not like that! I just wanted to see ya!
ليس الأمر هكذا، أردتُ لقاءك فحسب
Liar...
...أنت
Just kidding! The truth is--
...أمزح! في الحقيقة
Hello?
مرحباً؟
This is Mitsuaki. Could you put my father on?!
أنا ميتسواكي، هلّا أعطيت الهاتف لأبي؟
He's asleep at the moment. We're just about to leave...
،يبدو أنّ سيّدي... نائمٌ الآن كنّا على وشك المغادرة
I can't find Hideomi anywhere!
!لا أجد هيدومي في أيّ مكان
Where the heck did he--
...أين ذهب
Mitsuaki-sama!
!ميتسواكي-ساما
What's going on?! Where are you?!
!ما الخطب؟! أين أنت الآن؟
Right below you!
في الغرفة أسفلكم
Someone cut the lights and attacked me with--
أطفأ أحدهم الأنوار وهاجمني ...بشيء حادٍ من الخلف
Hey! Are you all right?!
!أأنت بخير؟
Mitsuaki-san! What's going on?! Mitsuaki-san!
ميتسواكي-سان! ما الذي يجري؟ !ميتسواكي-سان
Hideomi-san!
!هيدومي-سان
We gotta stop him!
!علينا إيقافه
No... why would he...
...لا يمكن... لمَ قد يقوم هيدومي-سان
Damn! It's locked from the inside!
!تبّاً! لا أستطيع فتحه !إنّه مقفل من الداخل
I'll get the master key!
سأذهب لجلب المفتاح البديل
Quickly!
!بسرعة
Yes!
!حاضر
I'll check around outside with the guards!
!سأكون في الخارج مع الحرّاس
Mitsuaki-san! What's going on?! Mitsuaki-san!
!ميتسواكي-سان! ما الخطب؟ !ميتسواكي-سان
Detective! Here's the key!
!حضرة المتحرّي! ها هو المفتاح
It's empty!
!لا أحد
The outside!
!ذهب خارجاً
Damn! He used a rope to escape!
!تبّاً! استعمل حبلاً وهرب
But where's Mitsuaki-san?!
!لكن أين ميتسواكي-سان؟
He's there. Down below.
إنّه موجود، أسفلنا
So, he fell onto the fence...
سقط على السياج إذاً؟
Is it true that the killer is Mr. Nagato's son, Hideomi-san?
أصحيحٌ أنّ الفاعل كان ابن السيّد ناغاتو، هيدومي-سان؟
No!
!كلا
Hideomi-san didn't do it! There must be some reason...
...لم يكن هيدومي-سان! لا بدّ من وجود سببٍ ما
He's still a murderer, whatever the reason!
!مهما كان السبب، يبقى قاتلاً
Give my Mitsuaki-san back...
...أرجعوا ميتسواكي-سان لي
But Hideomi-san would never do this...
لكنّ هيدومي-سان ليس شخصاً يُقدم على أشياء كهذه
Besides, we don't know he's the person we saw!
كما لا نستطيع الجزم أنّ !من رأيناه كان هيدومي-سان
She's right.
معها حق
We only saw someone with bandages on their face.
ما رأيناه هو شخص بضمادات تلفّ وجهه فحسب
Bandages?
ضمادات؟
Yes.
...نعم
Hideomi-san had burn scars all over his face...
يعاني هيدومي-سان من حروق على وجهه
We saw the killer shortly after 10:00 pm,
رأينا القاتل بعد العاشرة ليلاً بقليل
when everyone happened to be in the third-story bedroom.
عندما كان الجميع في غرفة نوم الرئيس في الطابق الثالث
"Everyone" being...?
الجميع؟
Me, Heiji, Ran, Conan, Take-san the butler, and Yasue-san.
كان المتواجدون في غرفة النوم هم أنا وهيجي-كن وران وكونان، كما كبير الخدم وياسوي-سان أي 6 أشخاص
What did you do when they left?
ماذا فعلتِ بعدما غادر الجميع؟
I stayed in the room with the president.
بقيتُ في الغرفة جوار الرئيس
To think the killer prepared that grappling hook to escape...
أحضّر القاتل ذاك الحبّل بالخطّاف سلفاً للهرب من الشرفة؟
There's no question that the killer used it.
لا شكّ في أنّ القاتل استعمله
It was still swaying when we checked around outside.
فقد كان لا يزال يتأرجح عندما وصلتُ مع الحرس هنا
And where's Hideomi-san?
أين هيدومي-سان إذاً؟
He's nowhere to be seen...
لم نجده في أيّ مكان
We looked for him while the police were on their way.
بحثنا عنه جميعاً قبل وصول الشرطة
So, Hideomi-san is clearly the killer.
من الجليّ أنّ المجرم هو هيدومي-سان
That can't be!
!لـ-لا يمكن
At any rate, we've found the killer's weapon, hat, and bandages.
بأيّ حال، وجدنا سلاح الجريمة والقبّعة والضمادات الخاصة بالمجرم
Analysis should prove--
...بالتحليل سوف
Say!
انظروا
What's this on his right hand? It's like he was stabbed by something.
ما هذا الجرح على يد الضحيّة اليمنى؟ يبدو أنّه طُعن بشيء
It's probably from the knife or the fence he fell on!
لعلّه من مهاجمة القاتل له بالسكّين !أو احتكاك يده بشيء أثناء سقوطه
Inspector!
!حضرة المفتّش
What is it, Takagi-kun?!
ما الخطب يا تاكاغي-كن؟
The exterior security cameras show nobody leaving after the murder!
لم تُظهر كاميرات مراقبة القصر الخارجية مغادرة أيّ أحد بعد الجريمة
So, the killer's...
...إذاً، القاتل
...still in the mansion!
!لا يزال في القصر
Oh, no!
!كلا
Hey!
...انتظر
The president!
...الرئيس الآن
What?! He's...
...ماذا؟! الرئيس
Damn! It's locked!
!تبّاً، إنّه مُقفل
Hey! Anyone in there?!
!أيوجد أحد في الداخل؟
What's all the ruckus?!
لمَ هذه الجلبة؟
What's with you all?
ما الذي جمعكم؟
What are you doing here?
ما الذي تفعلينه هنا؟
I came to see what all the noise was about.
أتيتُ بعدما سمعت الضوضاء
Where were you before then?
أين كنتِ قبل قدومك؟
I was irritated, so I had a drink in my room.
كنتُ منفعلة، فجلستُ أشرب في غرفتي
Alone?
بمفردك؟
Yes. While complaining to a friend on the phone.
أجل، بينما أتذمر لصديق لي على الهاتف
It must be the alcohol, but I can't recall who it was.
رغم أنّي لا أذكر من كان بسبب الشراب
Anyway, is it true that Hideomi killed Mitsuaki-san?
بغضّ النظر عن ذلك، أصحيحٌ أنّ هيدومي قتل ميتسواكي-سان؟
Yes, most likely...
...نعم، على الأرجح
Yeah, I figured he would eventually...
كما ظننت، توقّعت حصول ذلك يوماً ما
Those two would fight every time they saw each other.
فقد كانا يتشاجران كلّما تقابلا
They seemed to be friends since childhood,
يبدو أنّهما كانا على وفاق في الماضي بما أنّهما صديقا طفولة
but they were like cat and dog after the incident...
لكن أصبحا كثيري الشجار بعد تلك الحادثة
Incident?
تلك الحادثة؟
Yes. There was a big fire at a nearby inn twenty years ago.
نعم، نشب حريق كبير في نُزل مجاور قبل عشرين عاماً
Hideomi and Mitsuaki-san, high-schoolers at the time, passed by it.
مرّ به هيدومي وميتسواكي-سان اللذين كانا طالبين في الثانويّة وقتها
Mitsuaki-san tried to stop him, but Hideomi plunged into the flames
،حاول ميتسواكي-سان إيقاف هيدومي لكنّ الأخير اندفع للنيران
and rescued a little girl...
وأنقذ فتاةً صغيرة
Hyuga Miyuki, to be precise!
!كانت تلك هيوغا ميوكي هذه
Ah, hence the "bond of flames."
فهمت، هذه رابطة اللهب إذاً؟
Hideomi's face was burned as a result.
احترق وجه هيدومي جرّاء ذلك
After that, he quit school, shut himself in his room,
بعد الحادثة، ترك الدراسة وأغلق على نفسه في غرفته
and pretended to write novels.
وتظاهر بتأليف الروايات
No women got near him, of course.
لم تقترب منه أيّ فتاة بالطبع
She used that to make a pass at him,
استغلّت ذلك للاقتراب منه
get recommended as Father's secretary,
،حصلت على توصية لتكون سكرتيرة أبي
and even marry into the family!
!وفوق ذلك تزوّجت من العائلة
That's enough, Nobuko.
يكفي يا نوبوكو
Oh, you're awake?
أبي... كنتَ مستيقظاً؟
Yes, ever since everyone left the room in an uproar,
نعم، مُذ غادر الجميع الغرفة في هلع
though things have been fuzzy...
رغم أنّ ذهني مشوّش
Did anything strange happen afterward?!
هل حصل أمرٌ غريب بعد ذلك؟
Nothing at all. Hyuga-kun stayed with me until Ran-san arrived.
لم يحصل شيء، بقيت هيوغا-كن رفقتي طوال الوقت حتّى وصلت ران-سان
But this is no time to look for your first love now...
لكن لم يعد هذا وقتاً مناسباً ...للبحث عن محبوبتك الأولى
No, it isn't. Please forget about that.
لا، فلتنسَ الموضوع رجاءً
Tell me already! Why'd you bring me here!
يكفي مماطلةً وأخبرني لمَ جلبتني هنا؟
Ah, that?
ذاك؟
Actually, the president said he heard strange sounds last night.
في الواقع، قال الرئيس أنّه سمع أصوات غريبة البارحة
Strange sounds?
أصوات غريبة؟
Yeah.
نعم
Someone sprinting through the hall in the middle of the night,
صوت ركض أحدهم في الرواق في منتصف الليل
and something hitting something else, lots of times!
وصوت اصطدام شيء بشيءٍ آخر، عدّة مرات
Could it have been...?
...أيمكن أنّ ذلك
Yeah! Someone inside the house
نعم، كان أحد سكّان هذا المنزل
was doing something for tonight's murder!
!يقوم بشيءٍ لأجل جريمة الليلة
Me and my old man figured it was a burglar scoping the place out,
ظننتُ وأبي أنّه مجرّد لصّ يستكشف المكان
so we brought in security and called you.
فاستدعينا الحرّاس واتّصلنا بكم
We thought he'd show up again tonight,
اعتقدنا أنّه سيظهر مُجدداً الليلة بلا شكّ
but it was a life that was taken!
لكنّ ما سُلب كانت حياة شخص
A premeditated murder...
جريمة متعمّدة
But doesn't it seem strange?
لكن ألا ترى الأمر غريباً؟
That Mori Kogoro guy you made famous was here.
موري كوغورو الذي أصبح مشهوراً بسببك موجود هنا
The killer musta been really confident with his plan.
لا بدّ أنّ القاتل كان شديد الثقة بخطّته
Or he couldn't change his plan.
أو لم يستطع تبديل خطّته
What bothers me are the killer's items that were lying by the body.
ما يحيّرني هي أدوات القاتل التي كانت بجوار الجثّة
There was no need to drop the hat or bandages, never mind the weapon!
بعيداً عن السلاح، لم يكن عليه تضييع وقته بخلع القبعة والضمادات وهو يهرب
And the way the killer purposely showed his face to us...
...وإظهار القاتل لوجهه عمداً لنا
Almost as if to frame Hideomi-san...
كما لو كان يحاول إلفاق التهمة بهيدومي-سان
The only one who coulda done that is Nobuko-san, who left beforehand!
الوحيدة القادرة على ذلك هي نوبوكو-سان التي غادرت غرفة النوم مسبقاً
We then searched every nook and cranny of the mansion,
بعدها، فتّشنا القصر زاوية لزاوية
but Hideomi-san was nowhere to be found.
لكنّنا لم نجد هيدومي-سان أبداً
We were all about to give up two evenings later, when...
كنّا والشرطة على وشك الاستسلام ...بعد ليلتين من وقوع الجريمة
Can't find him anywhere, Inspector.
لم أجده في أيّ مكان سيّدي المفتّش
What?!
!ماذا؟
It's my fault Hideomi never married?!
!عدم زواج هيدومي كانت غلطتي؟
So, are you saying he held back for me?!
ماذا إذاً؟ أتقصدين أنّ هيدومي كان يمتنع لأجلي؟
No, I just meant that he thought highly of you...
...كلا، قصدتُ أنّه كان يراعيك بلطف
Miyuki-san! Wait!
...ميوكي-سان! ا-انتـ
Please stop! That pond is deep!
!توقّفي رجاءً! هذه البركة عميقة
But that pen is my father's keepsake! Without it, I...
!لكنّ ذاك القلم تذكارٌ من أبي ...دونه، لا أستطيع
Drain the water, quickly!
!صرّفوا الماء فوراً
Yes! Right away!
!حاضر
This is one filthy pond...
...يا لها من بركة متّسخة
Madam kept carp in it, but once she passed away...
،كانت سيّدة المنزل تربّي أسماك شبوط هنا ...لكن بعدما فارقت الحياة
Why?! Why did this have to happen?!
!لمَ؟! لمَ حصل هذا؟
Brother! Hideo-oniisama!
!أخي! أخي هيدومي
What is his estimated time of death?
ما وقت الوفاة المقدّر لهيدومي-سان؟
He's been dead for approximately 1.5 to 2 days.
كان ميتاً لقرابة يوم ونصف إلى يومين غالباً
Mitsuaki-san was pushed off the veranda
دُفِع ميتسواكي-سان من الشرفة
at 10:00 the night before last, 44 hours ago.
عند العاشرة قبل ليلتين، أي قبل 44 ساعة
If Hideomi-san drowned himself in this pond before we arrived,
إذا دخل هيدومي-سان هذه البركة قبل وصولنا
everything would fit.
وانتحر غرقاً، ستتصل جميع الخيوط
However, he didn't drown to death.
لكنّ سبب الموت لم يكن الغرق
We can't be sure until the autopsy,
لا يمكننا الجزم حتّى نجري التشريح
but he likely ingested poison before entering the pond.
لكنّه تجرّع سمّاً قبل دخوله البركة غالباً
The body didn't float up because of these rocks in his clothes.
سبب عدم طفو الجثّة هو هذه الصخور في ثيابه
So, Hideomi-san carried the rocks into the pond and poisoned himself?!
أتقصد أنّ هيدومي-سان دخل البركة والصخور معه وسمّم نفسه؟
He probably didn't want anyone to see him dead.
لعلّه لم يرد أن يراه أحد ميتاً
Still, as hostile as Hideomi-san and Mitsuaki-san were with each other,
لكن، مهما كانت العداوة ...بين هيدومي-سان وميتسواكي-سان
murder is a bit much...
...لا يزال القتل أمراً
It's possible. Hideomi-sama and Yasue-ojousama were very close,
ذاك مُحتمل، فهيدومي-ساما والآنسة ياسوي كانا مقرّبين كثيراً
so he was vehemently against her marriage with Mitsuaki-sama.
كان يعارض زواجها من ميتسواكي-سان بحدّة حتّى النهاية
So, he couldn't stomach the idea of losing his dear little sister
...لم يستطع تحمّل فقد أخته الغالية
to his bad friend...
...لصديقه السيّئ إذاً
Foolish child...
يا للفتى المغفل
Inspector Megure! Here's the lab report!
!مفتّش ميغوري! وصلت نتائج التحليل
Read it.
اقرأها
Right.
حاضر
"The marks on the knife match the wounds on Mitsuaki-san's arm,
تمّت مطابقة السكّين في مسرح الجريمة مع الجروح" على ذراع ميتسواكي-سان
and the blood on the knife matches his, as well.
كما تطابق دمّ السكّين مع دم ميتسواكي-سان
The hair follicles in the hat and bandages belong to Hideomi-san."
أيضاً، الشعيرات في القبعة والضمادات "تخصّ هيدومي-سان
That reminds me, there was a meter-long grappling hook
...بالمناسبة، كان هناك خيط رفيع بطول متر
in Mitsuaki-san's jacket pocket...
في جيب معطف ميتسواكي-سان
A grappling hook?!
خيط رفيع؟
Was the cut on his right hand from the knife, too?
أكان الجرح على كفّه اليمنى من السكّين أيضاً؟
No, it was different...
...كلا، كان مختلفاً لسببٍ ما
What about the blood type of the saliva on the knife?!
ماذا عن فصيلة الدم لصاحب اللعاب على السكّين؟
There wasn't any. Seems it was wiped off...
لم نجد شيئاً، يبدو أنّ السكّين مُسحت
Inspector! I found this paper in his pocket!
حضرة المفتّش! وجدتُ هذه الورقة !في جيب الضحيّة
"I'm not fit to marry you...
،لستُ مؤهلاً للزواج بك"
I choose death to atone for the sin I committed."
"اخترتُ الموت للتكفير عن الذنوب التي ارتكبتُها
This is his will! Miyuki-san! It's addressed to you!
!هـ-هذه وصيّة
Is it Hideomi-san's handwriting?
أهذا خطّ كتابة هيدومي-سان؟
Yes, it looks like it...
أجل، يبدو كذلك
I'll get some of his writings from his room...
سأجلب بعض كتاباته من غرفته
Miyuki-san! Here's the pen you dropped in...
...ميوكي-سان، هذا القلم الذي أسقطتِه
Wait--
...لحظة
Let her be.
دعيها وشأنها
I'll give it to her later.
سأعطيها القلم بنفسي لاحقاً
Hideomi-san...
...هيدومي-سان
This pen's really been burnt...
...قلم الحبر هذا مُحترق جدّاً
How odd...
...غريب
Yeah. This case is totally weird.
فعلاً، هذه القضيّة غريبة كثيراً
Even more unnatural is that will.
أكثر الأشياء غرابة هي تلك الوصيّة
It said, "The sin I committed."
"ذكر فيها "الذنوب التي ارتكبتُها
Meaning he wrote it after the murder!
أي أنّه كتبها بعد الجريمة
He didn't have time to write a will then!
!لم يكن لديه وقت لكتابة وصيّة آنذاك
Which means someone forged it or forced him to write it.
،ما يعني أنّ أحدهم زيّفها ...أو أرغمه على كتابتها
Either way, there's little doubt that someone drowned him
...بأيّ حال، يبدو أنّ لا شكّ في إغراق أحدهم لهيدومي-سان
with the will after poisoning him.
بعد تسميمه، ووضع الوصيّة معه
But the only time anyone got near the pond
لكن الوقت الوحيد الذي اقترب فيه أحد من البركة
was when we all went looking for him!
كان عندما ذهبنا للبحث عنه بعد وقوع الجريمة فقط
In other words, Hideomi-san had been murdered before it happened!
مما يعني أنّ هيدومي-سان !قُتل قبل وقوع الجريمة
Say, Hattori...
أخبرني يا هاتّوري
Have you ever killed someone?
أسبق وقتلتَ أحدهم؟
What the...?!
!ماذا؟
On the next Conan:
في الحلقة القادمة من كونان
The Case of the Eminent Family's Strange Deaths, Part 2.
قضيّة سلسلة حوادث الموت الغريبة للعائلة المرموقة الجزء الثاني
Next Conan's Hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Foutain pen.
قلم حبر
Next time:
...الحلقة القادمة
Solved, solved, solve.
"الحلّ، الحلّ، الحلّ"
The case is solved.
"جزء الحلّ"